<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>keerthanapg</title>
    <link>https://www.keerthanapg.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on keerthanapg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 17:37:56 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.keerthanapg.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Happy Orchid</title>
      <link>https://www.keerthanapg.com/posts/happyorchid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keerthanapg.com/posts/happyorchid/</guid>
      <description>I have a happy orchid plant
One that blooms white with a purple hue
Standing against my window nonchalant
Shining against the sun effortless
And then one day I decided to move
My happy orchid sat in a box
Waiting to see the light
But for a while it was left forgotten
In the darkness, while I sorted my affairs
It stood biding its wait
As dust settled on its glossy green leaves</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ending Aging: The Rejuvenation Breakthroughs That Could Reverse Human Aging in Our Lifetime</title>
      <link>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/endingaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/endingaging/</guid>
      <description>Aubrey de Grey, Michael Rae    Currently reading, stay tuned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Reviews</title>
      <link>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/</guid>
      <description>2021     Cryptoassets: The Innovative Investor&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Bitcoin and Beyond How to Avoid a Climate Disaster: The Solutions We Have and the Breakthroughs We Need 80,000 Hours: Find a fulfilling career that does good Options Trading Crash Course On Palestine Working Backwards: Insights, Stories, and Secrets from Inside Amazon The Art of Loving Attached: The New Science of Adult Attachment and How It Can Help YouFind - and Keep - Love Deep Work: Rules for Focused Success in a Distracted World How Innovation Works and Why It Flourishes in Freedom Competitive Strategy: Techniques for Analyzing Industries and Competitors Ending Aging: The Rejuvenation Breakthroughs That Could Reverse Human Aging in Our Lifetime  Click for older book reviews</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.keerthanapg.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keerthanapg.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>Self Driving Data Visualization     Data visualization for status quo on the race to build the self driving car. Demos - 2020, 2019 Code  RL bots on StarCraft 2     Built RL bots to play StarCraft 2 by adapting A3C algorithm and training in Deepmind-Blizzard StarCraft 2 environment Video demos, Paper  Multimodal emotion detection     Built a multimodal emotion recognition system with team of 3 in collaboration with Emotech AI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competitive Strategy: Techniques for Analyzing Industries and Competitors</title>
      <link>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/competitivestrategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/competitivestrategy/</guid>
      <description>Michael E Porter    Rating 2/5    This book was written more than 40 years ago and is textbook MBA material. Porters five forces analysis is a useful tool in any case study paradigm. Most of the book reads like common sense to me probably because much of its content has percolated into popular knowledge over the decades since it was written. I also think that its content has not particular suitable to address current tech industries where most of the wealth in the world is created today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Innovation Works and Why It Flourishes in Freedom </title>
      <link>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/innovation/</guid>
      <description>Matt Ridley    My rating 4/5    Matt Ridley&amp;rsquo;s How Innovation Works is best consumed as an audio book. The book traces the history of innovation in several industries including energy, public health, transport, food, communication and computers. The later half focuses on deriving rules about innovation given the history.
Among the stories of innovation, a case that stuck with me was the state of nuclear energy, which is a promising renewable source that is carbon free, but since iterating to improve the technology is rendered costly due to safety and environmental laws and guarantees, we are stuck with technology that is decades old.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Work: Rules for Focused Success in a Distracted World</title>
      <link>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/deepwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/deepwork/</guid>
      <description>Cal Newport    My rating: 5/5    Deep Work is a book about focusing. Given the barrage of distractions in today&amp;rsquo;s world, ranging from push notifications, social media and the expectation of responding fast to emails and work group chats, it becomes harder to do the type of work that requires deep focus.
The first few chapters talk about what deep work is and part 2 is about a few tips to get there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attached: The New Science of Adult Attachment and How It Can Help YouFind - and Keep - Love</title>
      <link>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/attached/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/attached/</guid>
      <description>Amir Levine, Rachel S F Heller    My rating: 4/5    Attached is a book on relationships, especially romantic relationships. It explains the evolutionary advantages to having a partner and how childhood experiences trigger different attachment styles.
Broadly, the book proposes that there are three types of attachment styles: anxious, avoidant and secure. The former two roughly account for a quarter of the population each and the latter accounts for about half.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Loving</title>
      <link>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/artofloving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/artofloving/</guid>
      <description>Eric Fromm    Rating 1/5    This is a highly recommended book on relationships. The core tenet is that western individualism dictates that if you focus on being the best version of yourself, love will follow. However, this book argues that that is far from enough and one needs to be good at loving to find and keep love.
While that advice is useful, I felt that the book was fraught with homophobia and transphobia having been written in the 1950s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working Backwards: Insights, Stories, and Secrets from Inside Amazon</title>
      <link>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/workingbackwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/workingbackwards/</guid>
      <description>Colin Bryar, Bill Carr    My rating: 4/5    Working Backwards is a business book on the story and culture of Amazon. The first part deals with the culture of Amazon ranging from hiring, organization, in house communication and metrics of achievement. Amazon culture places a lot of stress on its 14 leadership principles.
 A quote that stuck with me was : every company has a culture, if you don&amp;rsquo;t actively create it, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn about it once it is made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Palestine</title>
      <link>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/onpalestine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/onpalestine/</guid>
      <description>Noam Chomsky, Ilan Pappé    My rating: 5/5    I picked up &amp;ldquo;On Palestine&amp;rdquo; at the height of the Israel Palestine conflict in May 2021. It is an interesting summarization of Zionism and the history of Israel and is very poignant and concisely organised. The first part deals with the past, present, future of the conflict and context from within Israel and its relationship with the United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>80,000 Hours: Find a fulfilling career that does good</title>
      <link>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/80000hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/80000hours/</guid>
      <description>Benjamin Todd    Rating 3/5    If you&amp;rsquo;ve read Doing Good Better, you can totally skip this book. It expands into the research the 80000 hours organisation has done regarding careers and their impacts, so this book would be useful for young people looking to start a career or older folks looking to pivot/doing a reality check on their impact. Sometimes, the book reads like a curated webpage, which it totally is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Trading Crash Course: The #1 Beginner&#39;s Guide to Make Money With Trading Options in 7 Days or Less!</title>
      <link>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/optionstrading/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/optionstrading/</guid>
      <description>Frank Richmond    Rating 2/5    Skip and read investopedia. The last chapter on greeks and options strategies is actually useful though. The book, at times is very procedural.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.keerthanapg.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keerthanapg.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi
I am Keerthana! I am a roboticist at Google Brain: by day I convert coffee into code for training robots to do everyday tasks. I can talk endlessly about artificial intelligence and self-driving. I am also passionate about investing and stock markets, start-ups and technology, fitness, public policy in India and gender equality.
A part of my day is spent playing with my pug puppy Kiwi, who is monstrosity and innocence rolled into one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Avoid a Climate Disaster: The Solutions We Have and the Breakthroughs We Need</title>
      <link>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/billgates_climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/billgates_climate/</guid>
      <description>Bill Gates    My rating 5/5    This book was released around a month ago and is the most up to date compilation of issues and challenges surrounding climate change. What I love about this book is that it is markedly different in tone than what many climate activists advise - no angry rhetorics or morally high sounding stances. Crossing the Atlantic in a boat is not an option for everyone and asking the global population to give up on meat is simply non-practical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cryptoassets: The Innovative Investor&#39;s Guide to Bitcoin and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/cryptoassets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/cryptoassets/</guid>
      <description>Chris Burniske    Rating 3/5    I picked up this book because there are way too many keywords thrown around about cryptocurrencies and blockchain and you never know what you don&amp;rsquo;t know. Far from a comprehensive guide to &amp;ldquo;bitcoin and beyond&amp;rdquo;, this book could be summarized as &amp;ldquo;Bitcoin is great. Yields are great. You gotta invest&amp;rdquo;. While the initial few chapters go into explaining the technology and history of blockchain (Satoshi&amp;rsquo;s white paper on bitcoin, Vitalik Buterin&amp;rsquo;s work, Ethereum blockchain reversion to create Ethereum Classic, proof of stake/work), many of the latter chapters are far too repetitive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
