<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>keerthanapg</title>
    <link>https://keerthanapg.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on keerthanapg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 17:37:56 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://keerthanapg.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Horse gram, Kale and Sprouts salad with Rice</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/quarantine-meals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/quarantine-meals/</guid>
      <description>Served with a side of boiled rice.
Horse Gram Stir Fried: Originally posted here
Ingredients:
 Horse gram — 1 cup Salt — 1 tbsp Water — 2 cups Green chillies — 4 Red chilli powder — 0.5 tbsp Olive oil — 2 Tbsp Garlic — 3 cloves Curry leaves — optional  Preparation:
 Boil the horse gram with water and salt in a closed container / pressure cooker until cooked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reward is Not Not Enough: AGI and Reward Maximization</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/reward-is-not-not-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/reward-is-not-not-enough/</guid>
      <description>So I chanced by this post on LessWrong titled &amp;ldquo;Reward is Not Enough&amp;rdquo;. It is a rebuttal to the arguments presented in the paper &amp;ldquo;Reward is Enough&amp;rdquo; by Silver et al, which hypothesises that intelligence and its associated attributes are a result of reward maximization of an agent acting in its environment. Given the popularity of the LessWrong Forum, the pseudo-persuasive appeal of the article aided by technical jargon and for the sake of rationality, the post merits a deeper examination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Happy Orchid</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/happy-orchid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/happy-orchid/</guid>
      <description>I have a happy orchid plant
One that blooms white with a purple hue
Standing against my window nonchalant
Shining against the sun effortless
And then one day I decided to move
My happy orchid sat in a box
Waiting to see the light
But for a while it was left forgotten
In the darkness, while I sorted my affairs
It stood biding its wait
As dust settled on its glossy green leaves</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silence</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/silence/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
Silence
Like an ocean that leaps and bounds
Like a dragon that kicks and breathes fire, alive
Like a wide chasm between us
Our hearts are so far, far apart
Closed to each other
Though for a second we were so close
Like a bridge out into happiness
Like a hand that appears while drowning
But now I’m puzzled
Standing on a vast mountain range
Looking into caves very strange</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazy Sunday Morning</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/lazy-sunday-morning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/lazy-sunday-morning/</guid>
      <description>Lazy Sunday Morning Originally posted here
June 22, 2013
“It is a truth universally acknowledged, that a single man in possession of a good fortune must be in want of a wife.”
They have been special to me, and yet again, I stumbled upon these lines, as I sat up overnight to finish off David Baldacci’s thriller First Family. To talk of the book, a good plot, but the literature was just, mediocre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi
I am Keerthana! I am a roboticist at Google Brain: by day I convert coffee into code for training robots to do everyday tasks. I can talk endlessly about artificial intelligence and self-driving. I am also passionate about investing and stock markets, start-ups and technology, fitness, public policy in India and gender equality.
A part of my day is spent playing with my pug puppy Kiwi, who is monstrosity and innocence rolled into one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daybreak</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/daybreak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/daybreak/</guid>
      <description>Originally Posted on Medium
Tied up angel, wings battered
Shackled by the ankles
I lay rotting in the dirt
Among worms and spiders
Helpless and desolate
Like a forgotten ghost in the ceiling
But then I mustered my will,
Chewed up the chains
And through the broken attic window
I climbed
Cut my wings on the glass
Yet jumped into the moonlight
And took flight into an unknown
With broken chains on my ankles</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Much Ado About Nothing</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/much-ado-about-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/much-ado-about-nothing/</guid>
      <description>Much Ado about Nothing Originally posted here
A closer inspection of the ‘Rally for Rivers’ fanfare
Recently, Dr Rajendra Singh, who has spend decades working on community involvement in water management, winner of the Magsaysay Award and the Stockholm Water Prize, nicknamed the ‘Waterman of India’ called out the ‘Rally for Rivers’ movement. To quote, ‘this ‘Rally for Rivers’, is not for rivers. It is for the land, for money, for power, for fame and for name’ 1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Had Been</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/never-had-been/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/never-had-been/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
Pacing through a glass castle of mine
That is shattered in all but a second
At once when one is hit in the face by the chilling storm outside
How can you be mine but yet never have been mine
Feeling threatened in the most primal way
I’m alone, irrevocably so, irreversibly so
Even when engulfed in your arms
Listening to your heart beats so close</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When to use machine/deep learning to solve a problem?</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/when-to-use-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/when-to-use-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>When to use machine/deep learning to solve a problem? Originally posted here
Sometimes it can save a lot of time to stop and think if ML/DL is indeed the right approach to solve your problem rather than realising that after throwing a ton of data at a network without getting anywhere and potentially being outperformed by a simple classical algorithm. Here’s where ML shines:
 When the inputs are noisy When the solution cannot be described in human defined rules When the problem cannot be entirely defined and your solution needs to scale for diverse scenarios and edge cases When you can generate large amounts of data that is representative of your problem space When safety considerations allow redundancy for multiple methods to concur  Otherwise, don’t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Hefezopf</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/hefezopf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/hefezopf/</guid>
      <description>Recipe: Hefezopf Originally posted here
(This is a creative variant of a German Easter speciality known as Hefezopf)
Ingredients:
 Flour — 400 gms Yeast — 2 tbps Sugar — 1/2 cups Butter — 2 Tbps Water Baking soda — 1/2 tsp Jam — ~10 tsps Walnuts — 1/3 cups Chocolate — 1/3 cups Raisins — 1/3 cups  Mix the flour, yeast, sugar, butter, baking soda and water to create a smooth dough and let it rest for an hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Faceless Potrait</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/my-faceless-potrait/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/my-faceless-potrait/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
I have
I have a faceless portrait
One I’ve been holding close
For far too long
Etched over years, touched over every now and then
With each new dawn
The lines grow clearer
A faceless portrait hanging on a pedestal
Across my hallway
Waiting to come alive.
Beaming with pride and
Embellishing the sides
I only need a face to completion.
So I set out to find one</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Search For You</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/in-search-of-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/in-search-of-you/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
From Google Images
I walked down the road
Through alleys and corridors
In search of you
TRying to catch your eyes in the crowd
Sliding past glass windows for a sign
Of you
Your voice still rings in my ears,
As if playing with them constantly
Much like your lively, restless spirit
Your thoughts are fresh in my mind
They emerge from me
Become a hundred fireflies</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shooting Stars</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/shooting-stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/shooting-stars/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
If the moment is beautiful, is consistency necessary
If the eyes align, why do the stars need to
If happiness can precipitate in the now, who cares if the past and future are unmade
If the timeline is a mist, so what, if today is stark clear in a happy, mad hue
Can we count our sins after today, losing,
Can we contradict our values, shackles of morals, just for once</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Palpayasam</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/palpayasam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/palpayasam/</guid>
      <description>Recipe: Palpayasam Originally posted here
This is a traditional Malayali desert.
Expected time: 30 minutes
Ingredients:  Milk: 750mL Water Sugar: 2 Tbsp Rice: 2.5 Tbsp Ghee: 0.75 Tbsp Cashew: 50 grams Cardamom: 1 tsp  Procedure:  Melt the ghee and saute the rice and cashew in it for 1.5 minutes on high flame. Pour the milk, add sugar and cardamom and cook on low flame until rice is well cooked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to know before donating your hair?</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/donating-hair/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/donating-hair/</guid>
      <description>What to know before donating your hair? Originally posted here
This summer, I donated ten inches of my hair to Pantene Beautiful Lengths that make wigs for people suffering from cancer. In the US alone, every year about 100,000 people take chemotherapy for cancer treatment and undergo hair loss. The process of donating is fairly simple and easy though it’s important to keep a thing or two in mind.
Before - After  What to note:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why the Sabarimala entry issue is personal? Thoughts from your run-of-the-mill Malayali woman</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/sabarimala-entry-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/sabarimala-entry-issue/</guid>
      <description>Why the Sabarimala entry issue is personal?: Thoughts from your run-of-the-mill Malayali woman Originally posted here
.. and why this affects every Indian woman
Source: 12  On September 28th, 2018, the Supreme Court of India ruled that women be granted entry at Sabarimala 6. Among other things one should note:
 Can the temple do as they please? It is been found that Ayyappa devotees do not constitute a religious denomination and as such are not immune to outside interference 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If Only</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/if-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/if-only/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
Do I ever cross your mind?
If only as a brief flutter
Do I ever make you wind?
Your words, if only a stutter
Do you ever think about me?
Just one thought, if only, in your day
I wish it was my hands that you reached out for
I wish it was my lips that felt your kiss
I wish it was me that you woke up to</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures of Roomba: Tales of a Sentient Vacuum Cleaner</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/satient-vacuum-cleaner-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/satient-vacuum-cleaner-copy/</guid>
      <description>Adventures of Roomba: Tales of a Sentient Vacuum Cleaner Originally posted here
Part 1: Household Reflections It is an ordinary day for me. Rob and Jenny have left for work and I stroll the living room in a pointless trance, accompanied by a droning whizz of my motors. There is not a lot to life if you’re a cleaning robot. Unlike my cousins at the manufacturing shop, I do not go to the moon, I do not explore far away adventurous mines and be a hero saving people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Note Of Thanks</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/note-of-thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/note-of-thanks/</guid>
      <description>A note of thanks Originally posted here
“How strongly must one love knowing that you are unconvicted felons in the eyes of the law” — Menaka Guruswamy to bench of judges at Supreme Court, July 11 2018, during the hearing of petitions against section 377.
On 6th September 2018, the Supreme Court of the largest democracy of the world struck down section 377, a colonial-era law that decriminalises homosexuality. In a unanimous verdict, with passionately written judgements, the law of our land acknowledges the naturality of alternative sexuality and holds hope for further strides for Indian queer community, namely, marriage and civic equality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What did I learn/do differently this internship?</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/what-did-i-do-different-this-intern/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/what-did-i-do-different-this-intern/</guid>
      <description>What did I learn/do differently this internship? Originally posted here
I spent the summer in the San Francisco Bay area, Sunnyvale to be precise. I was interning at Mercedes Benz R&amp;amp;D and had a significantly different(good different) internship experience!
What did I do differently/What did I learn?
 Turned on extrovert mode: An internship or experience can become incredibly more fun if one can relate to other people in the same endeavour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Ginger-Cardamom Latte Tea</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/ginger-cardamom-latte-tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/ginger-cardamom-latte-tea/</guid>
      <description>Recipe: Ginger-Cardamom Latte Tea Originally posted here
It’s healthy, tasty and complements well when you’re working on tough assignments :P
Ingredients(makes 2 cups):
 Water — 1 cup Milk — 1 cup Sugar — based on preference Tea leaves — 2 tsps( I use Red Label brand and the strength of the tea depends on the brand somewhat. Green tea is weak) Ginger — small chunk (approx 2cm _ 2cm _ 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are optimal ways to donate for Kerala Flood Relief and Rescue if you live abroad?</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/kerala-flood-relief/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/kerala-flood-relief/</guid>
      <description>What are optimal ways to donate for Kerala Flood Relief and Rescue if you live abroad? Originally posted here
Here we’ve made a list of options for those based in the US/outside India to contribute to relief in Kerala floods. Each of them have been verified with a US based card. Do share more in links in comments, if you’re aware and we’ll analyse/verify/update.
1. The Chief Minister’s Distress Relief Fund website has recently added the functionality to accept international cards</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Draft of Death</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/draft-of-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/draft-of-death/</guid>
      <description>Originally Posted on Medium
A storm still raged in the midst of sea,
Where I had murdered you,
I lost you, far away
Your bloodstains mixed in the steam
Like a whirlpool of red
But far out in the sea where no one could see
Your face haunts me
My hands feeling, forever slippery with your blood
If I’ve slain, why are you still tied to me
Like an albatross around my neck</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/no/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/no/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
No,
I will not be the decked up doll,
Meant to please
Dumbed down by the appropriate amount
Draped in a tone of sugar and niceness
Intellect and insanity stuffed down to a small chest
Thrown into a sea
Sinking deep in its bellies
While the silent waves leave no hint
Of the tempest that rages within
I refuse to be the calm waves that kiss your feet</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Free</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/breaking-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/breaking-free/</guid>
      <description>Originally Posted on Medium
A dream hung on like raindrops on power cables overhead
A whole gleamy world in itself, a fairytale world
Full of promises and enforced perfection, off a story book
Walking on the tightrope of time,
I emerged from the drop unscathed in the heart
Or did the drop disappear altogether?
I do not know. I do not remember.
May be I was a fool that summoned the untrue</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Song of Hatred</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/a-song-of-hatred/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/a-song-of-hatred/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here
Photograph by Kevin Frayer 1
The photographer Kevin Frayer explains the scene: “I arrived to Cox’s Bazar, Bangladesh, in mid-September, a few weeks into the #Rohingya crisis. I was looking for places to photograph food aid because there was such a need for it and so little of it around. I was in an area where there was a crowd of people surrounding a truck. The scene was quite chaotic; people were shouting and reaching because they were obviously distraught and hungry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old and Young</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/old-and-young/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/old-and-young/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
Hopping over puddles, in a little pink frock
Hardly as tall as your knee cap,
Grasping tightly your index, with an entire little pink palm
Running to catch up with you,
Even as you lift and place me
Across small pools of water on the road
Over time your pace slowed and mine picked up
That you slowly heave to match my pace
Making me wonder when I outstripped you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: BlueBerry Pancakes</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/blueberry-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/blueberry-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>Recipe: Blueberry Pancakes Originally posted here
Preparation time: 10 minutes
Ingredients:
 Blueberries(fresh/dried):150g Pancake mix: 2/3 cup Water: 1/2 cup Sugar/sugar syrup: 1.5tsp/1.5 tbsp Butter: 1 tsp (optional) Cream cheese: 0.5 tsp (optional)  Procedure:
 Mash the blueberries such that there still are small lumps. Add the flour, water and sugar and mix thoroughly to remove flour lumps. Regulate water to alter consistency. Stop when it looks like dosa batter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rains, Thieves and Broken Dreams</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/rain-thieves-broken-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/rain-thieves-broken-dreams/</guid>
      <description>Rains, Thieves and Broken Dreams Originally posted here
Sourced from Google Images  Unlike most of India that receives rains once, Kerala has two rounds of monsoons. The first of the season arrives in June when the advancing monsoons make bountiful our harvest and rake up our GDP numbers. The brief spell of unperturbed sunlight is broken by the retreating monsoons, popularly called ‘Thulavarsham’ for they occur in the month of October/’Thula’, taking their leave from the country having toured thoroughly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Easy Baked Chicken</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/easy-baked-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/easy-baked-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Recipe: Easy Baked Chicken Originally posted here
Preparation time- 35 minutes
What you need:
 Tender chicken breasts — 0.5 pounds Olive oil — 2 table spoons Ginger garlic paste — 1 table spoon Pepper finely ground — 1 teaspoon Chilly powder — 0.25 teaspoon Garam masala — a pinch Turmeric powder— a pinch Lemon — a small slice Salt — as required  How to:
 Mix the powders and ginger-garlic to a paste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wall of Deceit</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/the-wall-of-deceit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/the-wall-of-deceit/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
Normal waves
Dampened by the sinking weights
of hurt over years
Unflinching today
Unmoved
Blanks eyes, and quizzical brows
Witness doubtful cries
Numb is the word
To what I feel
A game of rock, paper, scissors
Defeated are those who show their guts
Feeling small
Laying it out there
Bare, to be trampled on
To be a display
On the sidewalks of an uncaring passerby
Screams fall on deaf ears</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why’d you prevail?</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/why-you-prevail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/why-you-prevail/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
The contours of your face
Imprinted in my memories
Your face, that I’ve worshiped
Years went by
The wheel of time and with it the pages of history piled
But why,
Why don’t they erase your face from my heart
Why don’t they dirty it
Tear your pristine portraits
Why do you prevail
Like the bizarre sorrow of a cold night
Like the forgotten whisper in the whirling wind</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Case against Simultaneous Elections in India</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/case-against-simultaneous-elections/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/case-against-simultaneous-elections/</guid>
      <description>The Case against Simultaneous Elections in India Originally posted here
During his address on National Law Day 2017, PM Narendra Modi reiterated the push for implementing simultaneous elections in India, where Lok Sabha elections and Assembly polls of all states will be synced to happen once in 5 years, citing administrative difficulties and cost to exchequer. In the later half of this year, there has been much discussion about it, with Nitish Kumar 2, the Vice President 3, the controversial India Foundation 4 and other allies in support and regional parties and the left voicing their protest 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moods of Weather</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/moods-of-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/moods-of-weather/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
Shedding leaves and pretenses
Dropping off, pieces of one’s soul
Carried in the wind,
Passing on the living will
Leaving bare bones, branches behind
Shrinking in, staring within
Introverted shrugging to oneself
Quiet, unhindered
Preparing to be hit
By the the chill of loneliness
A lazy winter and creeping cold
Like cancer on your determination
Spreading eerily, binding you
Estranged frosty bite of a distilled purpose</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking Out On Sexual Harassment</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/speaking-out-on-sexual-harassment/much-ado-about-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/speaking-out-on-sexual-harassment/much-ado-about-nothing/</guid>
      <description>Speaking out on Sexual Harassment Originally posted here
#metoo.
When it has happened to Elizabeth Warren, why should you be reluctant to disclose.
Several times. Waking up to find a grown man sleeping next to me on the same berth, tangled in his lungi as a 10 year old on pilgrimage with parents. Or being grabbed by a frail shriveled old man in a crowded street as I visited town for the first time without parents at 13; wondering why my pee-pee area would be of interest to anyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bag of Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/bag-of-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/bag-of-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Originally Posted on Medium
A bag of thoughts we are
a tiny little star
sweltering pot
a burning core at its heart
likes and dislikes
ambitions and idiosyncracies
philosophies, glued together
in a weak concoction of will
A sphere of influence around
we hold close ones
As we journey through space,
carrying our identities
our baggage
in a journey called life
People come by, simering plasma like us,
held together by their will</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeeeeeeee :)</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/keeeeeee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/keeeeeee/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Quick and Easy Pasta</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/quick-easy-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/quick-easy-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here
Sharing successful tidbits from my reluctant adventures as a student cook. :)
Ingredients:
 Pasta — 1 cup Salsa sauce — 3 table spoons Cut up veggies — 3/5 cup Soy sauce — 1 tsp Garlic powder/paste — 1/2 tsp Ginger powder/paste — 1/4 tsp Chilli powder — 3/4 tsp Parmesan Cheese grated — 1/4 cup Mayonnaise — 1.5 tsp Pepper grated — 1 tsp Butter/ghee — 1 tsp Vegetable oil — 1 tsp Tomato sauce — 1 table spoon Salt — 1 tsp Turmeric powder — a pinch  Steps:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voices of a Forgotten Dream</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/voices-of-forgetten-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/voices-of-forgetten-dream/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
Third somebody in the room
Like an impenetrable wall
Between us.
The mind knits careful words
yearns for a soft feel of the cheeks
pinches in anticipation of the kiss.
Unsaid, undone.
Cheesy sugary eternals
Aborted, replaced with blank expressions
All the love means nothing
With a strange face in the room
Not intimate, never alone..
Not two, always three.
Cackling laughter that fills the room</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Eventful Dream</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/eventful-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/eventful-dream/</guid>
      <description>An eventful dream Originally posted here
This is an account of a dream I had today:
It was set in the years of the freedom movement in India and World War 2. Agricultural production had failed due to drought, war, plunder and loot by the imperialists to aid war supplies. My grandmother and I, two patriots on the run, lived in a small and claustrophobic mud-walled shack with a tiny door and window, in the basement of a busy school building.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>