<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>keerthanapg</title>
    <link>https://keerthanapg.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on keerthanapg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 17:37:56 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://keerthanapg.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/summer/</guid>
      <description>Summer in my backyard
Warm coffee in my belly
The sun simmers on my chest
Filling my bosom with love
The sun smiles at me from afar
My pug flashes her puppy eyes from my lap
Newly sprung summer flowers beam from around
And so I sit in my backyard on a carefree sunday
The wind hums a sweet little song
Caressing my wild hair like would a lover
Guiding falling leaves and pollen my way</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Truth</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/truth/</guid>
      <description>The truth is absolute and immutable.
The beauty of physics and our world is that
The truth is traveling at the speed of the light cone,
Sights and scenes of exactly what happened and was said
Scattering from one end of the universe to the other
Never to be muted
Perennially out there to be seen for those that want to see
The truth remains true
Regardless of whether one hundred or one million believes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bets and Business of Self Driving</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/self-driving-bets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/self-driving-bets/</guid>
      <description>Opinions presented in this article are that of the author alone and does not represent those of her employer.
As the new year drives in, let’s look back at some of the technological bets in self driving and where we are at with them today. Just last week Waymo and Cruise announced they are scaling to 3+ cities in the US, fully driverless. Waymo in Phoenix and SF, and Cruise in Phoenix, SF and Austin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undefeated</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/undefeated/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 10:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/undefeated/</guid>
      <description>It’s going to be okay
It’s going to be okay because I will make it so
I have cut chords with people who didn’t care
I have moved on and I am okay
I can do it a million more times
And still be okay
Why just okay? I will thrive.
I have said so many good byes
I have lost both people, money and places
I am still okay, I am happy even.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women and Effective Altruism</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/ea-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/ea-women/</guid>
      <description>Edit: This was cross posted to EA forum, and is a heavily downvoted post in their community. You can see the discussion here
A lot has been talked about SBF/FTX/EA but this coverage reminds me that is time to talk about the toxicity of the culture within EA communities, especially as it relates to women.
EA circles, much like the group house in Bahamas, are widely incestous where people mix their work life (in EA cause areas), their often polyamorous love life and social life in one amalgomous mix without strict separations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures of Roomba: Tales of a Sentient Vacuum Cleaner II</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/vacuum-cleaner-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/vacuum-cleaner-2/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 2: Flutterings of a Mechanical Heart Read Chapter 1: Household Reflections
The San Francisco Bay Area is a melting pot for machines like me. Our owners are like restless children, easily enchanted by technology, devices and their upgrades. Rob prides himself on being an early adopter and gets the new iPhone the day it releases to show off to his discord buddies. Jenny is a software engineer and quite a savvy one at it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the Grassroots and Reflections on EA</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/ea_disha_seema/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/ea_disha_seema/</guid>
      <description>Question about literal effective altruism. Let&amp;#39;s say you&amp;#39;re a random person in a non-western country, and you go around visiting various rural communities where means are limited, offering direct help.
What help / intervention would be most effective for your time and money?
&amp;mdash; Catherine Olsson (@catherineols) July 8, 2022  I spent 2 years organizing a volunteer community around and working with the Disha Seema School in Kharagpur. The school educates and boards ~270 kids from grades 1-12, and these kids mostly come from an underprivileged background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Mongolian Beef</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/mongolian-beef/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/mongolian-beef/</guid>
      <description>Preparation time - 1 hour
Cooking time - 10 minutes
Ingredients:  Beef flank - 1 pound Corn starch - 1/2 cup Olive oil - 1/2 cup Scallions - 5 Soy sauce - 1/2 cup Brown sugar - 3 Tbsp Ginger - grated - 1.5 tsp Garlic cloves - 4 grated Roasted red chilli - 10  How to:  Cut the beef into thin slices Marinate the beef for 1 hour with 2 Tsp corn starch, 2 tsp olive oil and 2 tsp soy sauce After one hour add the remaining corn starch and mix it until the beef is coated with a thin layer of corn starch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Broccoli Beef</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/broccoli-beef/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/broccoli-beef/</guid>
      <description>Preparation time - 15 minutes
Cooking time - 10 minutes
Ingredients:  Beef flank - 1 pound Corn starch - 1 Tbsp Olive oil - 1 Tbsp Broccoli - 0.5 pounds Soy sauce - 6 Tbsp Brown sugar - 2 Tbsp Ginger - grated - 1.5 tsp Garlic cloves - 4 grated Sesame seeds - to garnish Hot water - 1/2 cup Sesame oil - 2 Tbsp Black pepper powder - 1/2 tbsp  How to:  Cut the beef into thin slices  Cut the broccoli into small florets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embodiment is Indispensable for AGI</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/embodiment-agi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/embodiment-agi/</guid>
      <description>There are many paths on the road to AGI. Nando de Freitas recently wrote that “Scale is all you need” following the release of Deepmind’s Gato paper. Larger and larger transformers, with language interfaces doing supervised learning on large datasets is one such touted path. While Gato trains and evaluates on data from physical robots, there is a larger paradigm on getting to AGI that fully bypasses embodiment or robotics. This is the path pursued by OpenAI/Anthropic, who once famously disbanded their robotics team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amber Heart</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/amber-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/amber-heart/</guid>
      <description>Sourced from Google Images  If all you need is inside of you
If desires, like threads of entanglement,
Spawning from your heart
Can be cut, and let go
Like a forgotten coffee cup on a subway
If feelings can be let go
Like fragrance emanating from a flower
Without leaving it any less fragrant
Than before
If memories can stay on
Like frozen bugs in a heart of amber</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reward is Not Not Enough: AGI and Reward Maximization</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/reward-is-not-not-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/reward-is-not-not-enough/</guid>
      <description>So I chanced by this post on LessWrong titled &amp;ldquo;Reward is Not Enough&amp;rdquo;. It is a rebuttal to the arguments presented in the paper &amp;ldquo;Reward is Enough&amp;rdquo; by Silver et al, which hypothesises that intelligence and its associated attributes are a result of reward maximization of an agent acting in its environment. Given the popularity of the LessWrong Forum, the pseudo-persuasive appeal of the article aided by technical jargon and for the sake of rationality, the post merits a deeper examination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Happy Orchid</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/happy-orchid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/happy-orchid/</guid>
      <description>I have a happy orchid plant
One that blooms white with a purple hue
Standing against my window nonchalant
Shining against the sun effortless
And then one day I decided to move
My happy orchid sat in a box
Waiting to see the light
But for a while it was left forgotten
In the darkness, while I sorted my affairs
It stood biding its wait
As dust settled on its glossy green leaves</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ending Aging: The Rejuvenation Breakthroughs That Could Reverse Human Aging in Our Lifetime</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/endingaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/endingaging/</guid>
      <description>Aubrey de Grey, Michael Rae Currently reading, stay tuned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>For a full list of publications, check my google scholar page.
AutoRT: Embodied Foundation Models for Large Scale Orchestration of Robotic Agents  Orchestrating robotics agents for real world operation using a Robot Constitution Paper, Website Forbes, The Verge, Business Insider  RT-2: Vision-Language-Action Models Transfer Web Knowledge to Robotic Control  Training robots on internet scale image/text datasets Paper, Website Covered on the front page of New York Times, Forbes  RT-1: Robotics Transformer for Real-World Control at Scale  Adapting transformers for fast and scalable robot manipulation Paper, Github, Google AI Blog  SayCan: Grounding Language in Robotic Affordances  Using large language models for planning in robotics Demos, Paper - Best paper at RSS 2022 Scaling Robot Learning Workshop, Oral at CoRL 2022  Self Driving Data Visualization  Data visualization for status quo on the race to build the self driving car.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competitive Strategy: Techniques for Analyzing Industries and Competitors</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/competitivestrategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/competitivestrategy/</guid>
      <description>Michael E Porter Rating 2/5 This book was written more than 40 years ago and is textbook MBA material. Porters five forces analysis is a useful tool in any case study paradigm. Most of the book reads like common sense to me probably because much of its content has percolated into popular knowledge over the decades since it was written. I also think that its content has not particular suitable to address current tech industries where most of the wealth in the world is created today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Innovation Works and Why It Flourishes in Freedom </title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/innovation/</guid>
      <description>Matt Ridley My rating 4/5 Matt Ridley&amp;rsquo;s How Innovation Works is best consumed as an audio book. The book traces the history of innovation in several industries including energy, public health, transport, food, communication and computers. The later half focuses on deriving rules about innovation given the history.
Among the stories of innovation, a case that stuck with me was the state of nuclear energy, which is a promising renewable source that is carbon free, but since iterating to improve the technology is rendered costly due to safety and environmental laws and guarantees, we are stuck with technology that is decades old.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Work: Rules for Focused Success in a Distracted World</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/deepwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/deepwork/</guid>
      <description>Cal Newport My rating: 5/5 Deep Work is a book about focusing. Given the barrage of distractions in today&amp;rsquo;s world, ranging from push notifications, social media and the expectation of responding fast to emails and work group chats, it becomes harder to do the type of work that requires deep focus.
The first few chapters talk about what deep work is and part 2 is about a few tips to get there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attached: The New Science of Adult Attachment and How It Can Help YouFind - and Keep - Love</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/attached/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/attached/</guid>
      <description>Amir Levine, Rachel S F Heller My rating: 4/5 Attached is a book on relationships, especially romantic relationships. It explains the evolutionary advantages to having a partner and how childhood experiences trigger different attachment styles.
Broadly, the book proposes that there are three types of attachment styles: anxious, avoidant and secure. The former two roughly account for a quarter of the population each and the latter accounts for about half.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Loving</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/artofloving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/artofloving/</guid>
      <description>Eric Fromm Rating 1/5 This is a highly recommended book on relationships. The core tenet is that western individualism dictates that if you focus on being the best version of yourself, love will follow. However, this book argues that that is far from enough and one needs to be good at loving to find and keep love.
While that advice is useful, I felt that the book was fraught with homophobia and transphobia having been written in the 1950s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working Backwards: Insights, Stories, and Secrets from Inside Amazon</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/workingbackwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/workingbackwards/</guid>
      <description>Colin Bryar, Bill Carr My rating: 4/5 Working Backwards is a business book on the story and culture of Amazon. The first part deals with the culture of Amazon ranging from hiring, organization, in house communication and metrics of achievement. Amazon culture places a lot of stress on its 14 leadership principles.
 A quote that stuck with me was : every company has a culture, if you don&amp;rsquo;t actively create it, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn about it once it is made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Palestine</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/onpalestine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/onpalestine/</guid>
      <description>Noam Chomsky, Ilan Pappé My rating: 5/5 I picked up &amp;ldquo;On Palestine&amp;rdquo; at the height of the Israel Palestine conflict in May 2021. It is an interesting summarization of Zionism and the history of Israel and is very poignant and concisely organised. The first part deals with the past, present, future of the conflict and context from within Israel and its relationship with the United States. The second part discusses Gaza, genocide, violence and possible solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>80,000 Hours: Find a fulfilling career that does good</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/80000hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/80000hours/</guid>
      <description>Benjamin Todd Rating 3/5 If you&amp;rsquo;ve read Doing Good Better, you can totally skip this book. It expands into the research the 80000 hours organisation has done regarding careers and their impacts, so this book would be useful for young people looking to start a career or older folks looking to pivot/doing a reality check on their impact. Sometimes, the book reads like a curated webpage, which it totally is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Trading Crash Course: The #1 Beginner&#39;s Guide to Make Money With Trading Options in 7 Days or Less!</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/optionstrading/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/optionstrading/</guid>
      <description>Frank Richmond Rating 2/5 Skip and read investopedia. The last chapter on greeks and options strategies is actually useful though. The book, at times is very procedural.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silence</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/silence/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
Silence
Like an ocean that leaps and bounds
Like a dragon that kicks and breathes fire, alive
Like a wide chasm between us
Our hearts are so far, far apart
Closed to each other
Though for a second we were so close
Like a bridge out into happiness
Like a hand that appears while drowning
But now I’m puzzled
Standing on a vast mountain range
Looking into caves very strange</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazy Sunday Morning</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/lazy-sunday-morning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/lazy-sunday-morning/</guid>
      <description>Originally Written here
June 22, 2013
“It is a truth universally acknowledged, that a single man in possession of a good fortune must be in want of a wife.”
They have been special to me, and yet again, I stumbled upon these lines, as I sat up overnight to finish off David Baldacci’s thriller First Family. To talk of the book, a good plot, but the literature was just, mediocre. It seems like a tactic now, for writers to pull across a best-seller, by starring the President of the States in their plots, and most necessarily the NSA and FBI, and how it is of paramount importance to the lives of millions in America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi
I am Keerthana! I do research at Google Deepmind: I spend a lot of my time thinking about how to get scale robotics and build general purpose intelligence in the physical world.
The topics where I think I am an expert at are robotics, artificial intelligence and self-driving. I just wrote and published a textbook on &amp;ldquo;AI for Robotics&amp;rdquo;. I am on the look out for my next side project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Avoid a Climate Disaster: The Solutions We Have and the Breakthroughs We Need</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/billgates_climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/billgates_climate/</guid>
      <description>Bill Gates My rating 5/5 This book was released around a month ago and is the most up to date compilation of issues and challenges surrounding climate change. What I love about this book is that it is markedly different in tone than what many climate activists advise - no angry rhetorics or morally high sounding stances. Crossing the Atlantic in a boat is not an option for everyone and asking the global population to give up on meat is simply non-practical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/talks/</guid>
      <description>Cognitive Revolution Podcast, March 2024 Hosted by Nathan Labenz
 Neural Information Processings (NeurIPS), 2023 Speaker at 6th Workshop on Robot Learning
 International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2023 Panelist at Interactive Learning with Implicit Human Feedback Workshop moderated by Anca Dragan Watch recording of Panel 1
Watch recording of Panel 2
Cognitive Revolution Podcast, March 2023 Hosted by Nathan Labenz and Erik Torenberg
 ML Collective, Deep Learning Classics and Trends, March 2023 Hosted by Rosanne Liu, we talk about recent advances in robotics and recipes to build a Robotics Foundation Model</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cryptoassets: The Innovative Investor&#39;s Guide to Bitcoin and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/cryptoassets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/cryptoassets/</guid>
      <description>Chris Burniske Rating 3/5 I picked up this book because there are way too many keywords thrown around about cryptocurrencies and blockchain and you never know what you don&amp;rsquo;t know. Far from a comprehensive guide to &amp;ldquo;bitcoin and beyond&amp;rdquo;, this book could be summarized as &amp;ldquo;Bitcoin is great. Yields are great. You gotta invest&amp;rdquo;. While the initial few chapters go into explaining the technology and history of blockchain (Satoshi&amp;rsquo;s white paper on bitcoin, Vitalik Buterin&amp;rsquo;s work, Ethereum blockchain reversion to create Ethereum Classic, proof of stake/work), many of the latter chapters are far too repetitive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daybreak</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/daybreak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/daybreak/</guid>
      <description>Originally Posted on Medium
Sourced from Google Images  Tied up angel, wings battered
Shackled by the ankles
I lay rotting in the dirt
Among worms and spiders
Helpless and desolate
Like a forgotten ghost in the ceiling
But then I mustered my will,
Chewed up the chains
And through the broken attic window
I climbed
Cut my wings on the glass
Yet jumped into the moonlight
And took flight into an unknown</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Promised Land</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/a_promised_land/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/a_promised_land/</guid>
      <description>Barack Obama Rating 4.36/5 Since I am from India, I found the book interesting only up until the point Obama became president. Until that event, the book describes in erudite passion Obama&amp;rsquo;s youth and his journey to the presidency. His conviction is admirable and his courage/confidence is worth envying. What struck me most was his sense of idealism and how much he stood by it over the years even if others were weary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great at Work: How Top Performers Do Less, Work Better, and Achieve More</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/great_at_work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/great_at_work/</guid>
      <description>Morten T. Hansen Rating 3.79/5 This is a fairly useful book. I picked it up as I started my first job to be able to get better on managing work. Most insights from the book are derived from a fairly generalised and large survey of workers in the United States. These derivations are also quite practical to be put to use in daily life and helps you anticipate outcomes of organisational decisions and decide how to participate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bullshit Jobs: A Theory</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/bullshit_jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/bullshit_jobs/</guid>
      <description>David Graeber My rating: 4.02/5 David Graeber wrote this book after his very famous essay by the same name. It draws on several anecdotes and responses he received after writing the essay. However, a peculiar thing to note is that despite being an anthropologist from Oxford, this is not based on original research but one could note that some research is cited to support the assertions made in the book. The first few chapters are very useful in understanding the time of useless jobs that can exist in the industry, especially private industry, how to identify one, hidden unemployment ( several parties doing the work of one person), etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Horse gram, Kale and Sprouts salad with Rice</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/quarantine-meals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/quarantine-meals/</guid>
      <description>Served with a side of boiled rice.
Horse Gram Stir Fried: Originally Written here
Ingredients:
 Horse gram — 1 cup Salt — 1 tbsp Water — 2 cups Green chillies — 4 Red chilli powder — 0.5 tbsp Olive oil — 2 Tbsp Garlic — 3 cloves Curry leaves — optional  Preparation:
 Boil the horse gram with water and salt in a closed container / pressure cooker until cooked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Much Ado About Nothing</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/much-ado-about-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/much-ado-about-nothing/</guid>
      <description>Originally Written here
A closer inspection of the ‘Rally for Rivers’ fanfare
Recently, Dr Rajendra Singh, who has spend decades working on community involvement in water management, winner of the Magsaysay Award and the Stockholm Water Prize, nicknamed the ‘Waterman of India’ called out the ‘Rally for Rivers’ movement. To quote, ‘this ‘Rally for Rivers’, is not for rivers. It is for the land, for money, for power, for fame and for name’ 1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Had Been</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/never-had-been/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/never-had-been/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
Image source : here  Pacing through a glass castle of mine
That is shattered in all but a second
At once when one is hit in the face by the chilling storm outside
How can you be mine but yet never have been mine
Feeling threatened in the most primal way
I’m alone, irrevocably so, irreversibly so
Even when engulfed in your arms
Listening to your heart beats so close</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When to use machine/deep learning to solve a problem?</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/when-to-use-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/when-to-use-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here
Sometimes it can save a lot of time to stop and think if ML/DL is indeed the right approach to solve your problem rather than realising that after throwing a ton of data at a network without getting anywhere and potentially being outperformed by a simple classical algorithm. Here’s where ML shines:
 When the inputs are noisy When the solution cannot be described in human defined rules When the problem cannot be entirely defined and your solution needs to scale for diverse scenarios and edge cases When you can generate large amounts of data that is representative of your problem space When safety considerations allow redundancy for multiple methods to concur  Otherwise, don’t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Hefezopf</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/hefezopf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/hefezopf/</guid>
      <description>Originally Written here
(This is a creative variant of a German Easter speciality known as Hefezopf)
Ingredients:
 Flour — 400 gms Yeast — 2 tbps Sugar — 1/2 cups Butter — 2 Tbps Water Baking soda — 1/2 tsp Jam — ~10 tsps Walnuts — 1/3 cups Chocolate — 1/3 cups Raisins — 1/3 cups  Mix the flour, yeast, sugar, butter, baking soda and water to create a smooth dough and let it rest for an hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Faceless Potrait</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/my-faceless-potrait/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/my-faceless-potrait/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
Source: Google Images   I have a faceless portrait
One I’ve been holding close
For far too long
Etched over years, touched over every now and then
With each new dawn
The lines grow clearer
A faceless portrait hanging on a pedestal
Across my hallway
Waiting to come alive.
Beaming with pride and
Embellishing the sides
I only need a face to completion.
So I set out to find one</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Search of You</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/in-search-of-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/in-search-of-you/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
Sourced from Google Images  I walked down the road
Through alleys and corridors
In search of you
TRying to catch your eyes in the crowd
Sliding past glass windows for a sign
Of you
Your voice still rings in my ears,
As if playing with them constantly
Much like your lively, restless spirit
Your thoughts are fresh in my mind
They emerge from me
Become a hundred fireflies</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factfulness: Ten Reasons We&#39;re Wrong About the World – and Why Things Are Better Than You Think</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/factfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/factfulness/</guid>
      <description>Hans Rosling, Ola Rosling, Anna Rosling Rönnlund My rating: 4.36/5 This book, written by Swedish physician Hans Rosling and published posthumously is an optimistic and fact based take on human development with a focus on health and medicine. Primarily written for a western audience this book assumes the prevalence of a premise of western superiority and then seeks to demolish it. As someone from a developing country, having grown up seeing India change and grow around me, having been witness to notably compounding and progressive improvement across generations in my own family, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t as surprised as the author expected the reader to be; as such I felt it intended to speak to a white person in a developed country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ഖസാക്കിന്റെ ഇതിഹാസം | Khasakkinte Ithihasam</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/khasakkinte_ithihasam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/khasakkinte_ithihasam/</guid>
      <description>O.V. Vijayan Rating 4.11/5 I picked up this critically acclaimed classic to better understand Malayalam literature and life in rural Kerala. It is not one big epic but a collection of incidents set in and around a village that is 10 minutes from my home in Palakkad. The writer exercises abundant subtlely in his narration and bounces forth from reality and imagination so much so that much is left to the interpretation of the reader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shooting Stars</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/shooting-stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/shooting-stars/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
Clicked by Tom Eliasson, from Google Images  If the moment is beautiful, is consistency necessary
If the eyes align, why do the stars need to
If happiness can precipitate in the now, who cares if the past and future are unmade
If the timeline is a mist, so what, if today is stark clear in a happy, mad hue
Can we count our sins after today, losing,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Palpayasam</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/palpayasam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/palpayasam/</guid>
      <description>Originally Written here
This is a traditional Malayali desert.
Expected time: 30 minutes
Ingredients:  Milk: 750mL Water Sugar: 2 Tbsp Rice: 2.5 Tbsp Ghee: 0.75 Tbsp Cashew: 50 grams Cardamom: 1 tsp  Procedure:  Melt the ghee and saute the rice and cashew in it for 1.5 minutes on high flame. Pour the milk, add sugar and cardamom and cook on low flame until rice is well cooked. Stir continuously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Elephant in the Brain: Hidden Motives in Everyday Life</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/elephant_in_brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/elephant_in_brain/</guid>
      <description>Kevin Simler, Robin Hanson My rating: 4.02/5 The first few chapters are very insightful and exciting, especially the part about subtle interactions and deceptions we consciously and subconsciously have cultivated as a society. However, towards the end it gets fairly repetitive and embarks on the same points for far too long. All in all, great read about human psychology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to know before donating your hair?</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/donating-hair/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/donating-hair/</guid>
      <description>Originally Written here
This summer, I donated ten inches of my hair to Pantene Beautiful Lengths that make wigs for people suffering from cancer. In the US alone, every year about 100,000 people take chemotherapy for cancer treatment and undergo hair loss. The process of donating is fairly simple and easy though it’s important to keep a thing or two in mind.
Before - After  What to note:
 Talk to others before you do it and be very sure you want to donate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why the Sabarimala entry issue is personal? Thoughts from your run-of-the-mill Malayali woman</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/sabarimala-entry-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/sabarimala-entry-issue/</guid>
      <description>.. and why this affects every Indian woman
Originally Written here
Source  On September 28th, 2018, the Supreme Court of India ruled that women be granted entry at Sabarimala 6. Among other things one should note:
 Can the temple do as they please? It is been found that Ayyappa devotees do not constitute a religious denomination and as such are not immune to outside interference 1. The temple is a public place 2 and therefore when an Agama/tradition contradicts a fundamental right, the constitution prevails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If Only</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/if-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/if-only/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
Sourced from Google Images  Do I ever cross your mind?
If only as a brief flutter
Do I ever make you wind?
Your words, if only a stutter
Do you ever think about me?
Just one thought, if only, in your day
I wish it was my hands that you reached out for
I wish it was my lips that felt your kiss
I wish it was me that you woke up to</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures of Roomba: Tales of a Sentient Vacuum Cleaner</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/satient-vacuum-cleaner-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/satient-vacuum-cleaner-copy/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here
Part 1: Household Reflections It is an ordinary day for me. Rob and Jenny have left for work and I stroll the living room in a pointless trance, accompanied by a droning whizz of my motors. There is not a lot to life if you’re a cleaning robot. Unlike my cousins at the manufacturing shop, I do not go to the moon, I do not explore far away adventurous mines and be a hero saving people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Note Of Thanks</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/note-of-thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/note-of-thanks/</guid>
      <description>A note of thanks Originally Written here
“How strongly must one love knowing that you are unconvicted felons in the eyes of the law” — Menaka Guruswamy to bench of judges at Supreme Court, July 11 2018, during the hearing of petitions against section 377.
On 6th September 2018, the Supreme Court of the largest democracy of the world struck down section 377, a colonial-era law that decriminalises homosexuality. In a unanimous verdict, with passionately written judgements, the law of our land acknowledges the naturality of alternative sexuality and holds hope for further strides for Indian queer community, namely, marriage and civic equality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What did I learn/do differently this internship?</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/what-did-i-do-different-this-intern/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/tech/what-did-i-do-different-this-intern/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here
I spent the summer in the San Francisco Bay area, Sunnyvale to be precise. I was interning at Mercedes Benz R&amp;amp;D and had a significantly different(good different) internship experience!
What did I do differently/What did I learn?
 Turned on extrovert mode: An internship or experience can become incredibly more fun if one can relate to other people in the same endeavour. I was marginally more successful at this since I took a voluntary effort to talk and I must say it paid off very well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Ginger-Cardamom Latte Tea</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/ginger-cardamom-latte-tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/ginger-cardamom-latte-tea/</guid>
      <description>Originally Written here
It’s healthy, tasty and complements well when you’re working on tough assignments :P
Ingredients(makes 2 cups):
 Water — 1 cup Milk — 1 cup Sugar — based on preference Tea leaves — 2 tsps( I use Red Label brand and the strength of the tea depends on the brand somewhat. Green tea is weak) Ginger — small chunk (approx 2cm _ 2cm _ 0.5cm) Cardamom seeds — 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are optimal ways to donate for Kerala Flood Relief and Rescue if you live abroad?</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/kerala-flood-relief/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/kerala-flood-relief/</guid>
      <description>What are optimal ways to donate for Kerala Flood Relief and Rescue if you live abroad? Originally Written here
Here we’ve made a list of options for those based in the US/outside India to contribute to relief in Kerala floods. Each of them have been verified with a US based card. Do share more in links in comments, if you’re aware and we’ll analyse/verify/update.
1. The Chief Minister’s Distress Relief Fund website has recently added the functionality to accept international cards</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Draft of Death</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/draft-of-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/draft-of-death/</guid>
      <description>Originally Posted on Medium
A storm still raged in the midst of sea,
Where I had murdered you,
I lost you, far away
Your bloodstains mixed in the steam
Like a whirlpool of red
But far out in the sea where no one could see
Your face haunts me
My hands feeling, forever slippery with your blood
If I’ve slain, why are you still tied to me
Like an albatross around my neck</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/no/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/no/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
No,
I will not be the decked up doll,
Meant to please
Dumbed down by the appropriate amount
Draped in a tone of sugar and niceness
Intellect and insanity stuffed down to a small chest
Thrown into a sea
Sinking deep in its bellies
While the silent waves leave no hint
Of the tempest that rages within
I refuse to be the calm waves that kiss your feet</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Free</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/breaking-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/breaking-free/</guid>
      <description>Originally Posted on Medium
A dream hung on like raindrops on power cables overhead
A whole gleamy world in itself, a fairytale world
Full of promises and enforced perfection, off a story book
Walking on the tightrope of time,
I emerged from the drop unscathed in the heart
Or did the drop disappear altogether?
I do not know. I do not remember.
May be I was a fool that summoned the untrue</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Song of Hatred</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/a-song-of-hatred/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/a-song-of-hatred/</guid>
      <description>Originally Written here
Photograph by Kevin Frayer  The photographer Kevin Frayer explains the scene: “I arrived to Cox’s Bazar, Bangladesh, in mid-September, a few weeks into the #Rohingya crisis. I was looking for places to photograph food aid because there was such a need for it and so little of it around. I was in an area where there was a crowd of people surrounding a truck. The scene was quite chaotic; people were shouting and reaching because they were obviously distraught and hungry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old and Young</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/old-and-young/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/old-and-young/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
Sourced from Google Images  Hopping over puddles, in a little pink frock
Hardly as tall as your knee cap,
Grasping tightly your index, with an entire little pink palm
Running to catch up with you,
Even as you lift and place me
Across small pools of water on the road
Over time your pace slowed and mine picked up
That you slowly heave to match my pace</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rains, Thieves and Broken Dreams</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/rain-thieves-broken-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/rain-thieves-broken-dreams/</guid>
      <description>Originally Written here
Unlike most of India that receives rains once, Kerala has two rounds of monsoons. The first of the season arrives in June when the advancing monsoons make bountiful our harvest and rake up our GDP numbers. The brief spell of unperturbed sunlight is broken by the retreating monsoons, popularly called ‘Thulavarsham’ for they occur in the month of October/’Thula’, taking their leave from the country having toured thoroughly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Easy Baked Chicken</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/easy-baked-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/easy-baked-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Originally Written here
Preparation time- 35 minutes
What you need:
 Tender chicken breasts — 0.5 pounds Olive oil — 2 table spoons Ginger garlic paste — 1 table spoon Pepper finely ground — 1 teaspoon Chilly powder — 0.25 teaspoon Garam masala — a pinch Turmeric powder— a pinch Lemon — a small slice Salt — as required  How to:
 Mix the powders and ginger-garlic to a paste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wall of Deceit</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/the-wall-of-deceit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/the-wall-of-deceit/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
Normal waves
Dampened by the sinking weights
of hurt over years
Unflinching today
Unmoved
Blanks eyes, and quizzical brows
Witness doubtful cries
Numb is the word
To what I feel
A game of rock, paper, scissors
Defeated are those who show their guts
Feeling small
Laying it out there
Bare, to be trampled on
To be a display
On the sidewalks of an uncaring passerby
Screams fall on deaf ears</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why’d you prevail?</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/why-you-prevail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/why-you-prevail/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
Sourced from Google Images  The contours of your face
Imprinted in my memories
Your face, that I’ve worshiped
Years went by
The wheel of time and with it the pages of history piled
But why,
Why don’t they erase your face from my heart
Why don’t they dirty it
Tear your pristine portraits
Why do you prevail
Like the bizarre sorrow of a cold night</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Case against Simultaneous Elections in India</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/case-against-simultaneous-elections/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/case-against-simultaneous-elections/</guid>
      <description>The Case against Simultaneous Elections in India Originally Written here
During his address on National Law Day 2017, PM Narendra Modi reiterated the push for implementing simultaneous elections in India, where Lok Sabha elections and Assembly polls of all states will be synced to happen once in 5 years, citing administrative difficulties and cost to exchequer. In the later half of this year, there has been much discussion about it, with Nitish Kumar 2, the Vice President 3, the controversial India Foundation 4 and other allies in support and regional parties and the left voicing their protest 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moods of Weather</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/moods-of-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/moods-of-weather/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
Image Reference  Shedding leaves and pretenses
Dropping off, pieces of one’s soul
Carried in the wind,
Passing on the living will
Leaving bare bones, branches behind
Shrinking in, staring within
Introverted shrugging to oneself
Quiet, unhindered
Preparing to be hit
By the the chill of loneliness
A lazy winter and creeping cold
Like cancer on your determination
Spreading eerily, binding you
Estranged frosty bite of a distilled purpose</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking Out On Sexual Harassment</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/speaking-out-on-sexual-harassment/much-ado-about-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/speaking-out-on-sexual-harassment/much-ado-about-nothing/</guid>
      <description>Speaking out on Sexual Harassment Originally Written here
#metoo.
When it has happened to Elizabeth Warren, why should you be reluctant to disclose.
Several times. Waking up to find a grown man sleeping next to me on the same berth, tangled in his lungi as a 10 year old on pilgrimage with parents. Or being grabbed by a frail shriveled old man in a crowded street as I visited town for the first time without parents at 13; wondering why my pee-pee area would be of interest to anyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bag of Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/bag-of-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/bag-of-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Originally Posted on Medium
A bag of thoughts we are
a tiny little star
sweltering pot
a burning core at its heart
likes and dislikes
ambitions and idiosyncracies
philosophies, glued together
in a weak concoction of will
A sphere of influence around
we hold close ones
As we journey through space,
carrying our identities
our baggage
in a journey called life
People come by, simering plasma like us,
held together by their will</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeeeeeeee :)</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/keeeeeee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/keeeeeee/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Quick and Easy Pasta</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/quick-easy-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/quick-easy-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Originally Written here
Sharing successful tidbits from my reluctant adventures as a student cook. :)
Ingredients:
 Pasta — 1 cup Salsa sauce — 3 table spoons Cut up veggies — 3/5 cup Soy sauce — 1 tsp Garlic powder/paste — 1/2 tsp Ginger powder/paste — 1/4 tsp Chilli powder — 3/4 tsp Parmesan Cheese grated — 1/4 cup Mayonnaise — 1.5 tsp Pepper grated — 1 tsp Butter/ghee — 1 tsp Vegetable oil — 1 tsp Tomato sauce — 1 table spoon Salt — 1 tsp Turmeric powder — a pinch  Steps:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voices of a Forgotten Dream</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/voices-of-forgetten-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/poetry/voices-of-forgetten-dream/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium
From Google Images  Third somebody in the room
Like an impenetrable wall
Between us.
The mind knits careful words
yearns for a soft feel of the cheeks
pinches in anticipation of the kiss.
Unsaid, undone.
Cheesy sugary eternals
Aborted, replaced with blank expressions
All the love means nothing
With a strange face in the room
Not intimate, never alone..
Not two, always three.
Cackling laughter that fills the room</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Eventful Dream</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/eventful-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/eventful-dream/</guid>
      <description>Originally Written here
This is an account of a dream I had today:
It was set in the years of the freedom movement in India and World War 2. Agricultural production had failed due to drought, war, plunder and loot by the imperialists to aid war supplies. My grandmother and I, two patriots on the run, lived in a small and claustrophobic mud-walled shack with a tiny door and window, in the basement of a busy school building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Positivity: Stop Negative Thought Patterns by Changing Your Brain Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/science_of_positivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/science_of_positivity/</guid>
      <description>Loretta Graziano Breuning My rating: 3.57/5 The Science of Positivity talks about five hormones and neurotransmitters: serotonin, oxytocin, dopamine, endorphin and cortisol and how they affect our everyday behaviour and rationality. The book draws parallels between human brain and an early mammal brain when it comes to decision making. As for me, it helped me be more conscious of negative thought patterns and make an active effort to be more positive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Policy in India: Oxford India Short Introductions</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/public_policy_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/public_policy_india/</guid>
      <description>Rajesh Chakrabarti, Kaushiki Sanyal My rating: 3.97/5 This is a brief introduction to public policy in India. It discusses formulation, analysis and implementation/revision of policy interventions in the Indian context and uses case studies to investigate into examples of good and bad policy implemented in India. A key learning has been about mathematical models used to collect evidence for policy intervention, such as RCTs and difference-in-difference. Examples that took me by surprise were that of the Balika Cycle Yojana in Bihar and mandating of Aadhar for MGNREGS and pensions in Andhra Pradesh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Holes and Baby Universes and Other Essays</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/black_holes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/black_holes/</guid>
      <description>Stehpen Hawking My rating: 4.17/5 Collection of essays about black holes, quantum mechanics and unified theory that is mostly easy to follow. Hawkings also extrapolates on concepts such as imaginary time, that were controversial parts of &amp;lsquo;A Brief History of Time&amp;rsquo;. The beginning few essays, of his childhood and his fight with ALS, are quite forthcoming and transparent in narrative. The snarky humor at times is an entertaining surprise. It&amp;rsquo;s a short book with lots to learn and it glued me to my seat for two days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Option B: Facing Adversity, Building Resilience, and Finding Joy</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/optionb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/optionb/</guid>
      <description>Sheryl Sandberg, Adam M. Grant My rating: 3.85/5 Option B is a book that advises on countering adverse situations routed in Sheryl Sandberg&amp;rsquo;s autobiographical account. What makes an adverse experience worse is 3Ps: personalisation(that you&amp;rsquo;re to blame), permanence(that it&amp;rsquo;ll last forever) and pervasiveness(that it affects other areas of life) and one should strive to overcome these thought patterns to build resilience. It also talks about how to deal with people who&amp;rsquo;ve recently encountered an adversity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting to Yes: Negotiating Agreement Without Giving In</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/getting_to_yes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/getting_to_yes/</guid>
      <description>Roger Fisher, William Ury, Bruce Patton My rating: 3.94/5 This is a book on negotiation that talks about power, ethics, tactics and counter moves in negotiation. It is more about getting what you deserve than gaining more than your fair share. It makes sense to separate the people from the problem, focus on interests over positions, evaluate your alternatives and make the pie bigger for everyone. What I loved the most was the section on common negotiation tactics and how to identify and respond to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love&#39;s Executioner and Other Tales of Psychotherapy</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/loves_executioner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/loves_executioner/</guid>
      <description>Irvin D. Yalom My rating: 4.24/5 This book is an account of Yalom&amp;rsquo;s selected cases as a psychoanalyst. It&amp;rsquo;ll impart confidence to your own analysis of human nature and behaviours, and offer to enrich them with the practices and wisdom of an academic insider. What I found most surprising was dream interpretation. While I&amp;rsquo;ve always found dreams as abstract representations of everyday randomness, it was astonishing to realise that dreams are a clinically established means to investigate what troubles the mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hard Thing About Hard Things: Building a Business When There Are No Easy Answers</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/hard_thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/hard_thing/</guid>
      <description>Ben Horowitz My rating: 4.23/5 This is a wonderful book! It gives an insider&amp;rsquo;s view of how it feels to run a startup and decide between conflicting options. It makes even more sense if you&amp;rsquo;ve already run a startup to be able to understand the nuances and the significance of these choices and their context. From hiring for greatness than lack of weakness, networking to spot the PR managers that can turn chicken shit to chicken salad, from management debt to managing profanity in company culture, this book explores a number of pain points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poor Economics: A Radical Rethinking of the Way to Fight Global Poverty</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/poor_economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/poor_economics/</guid>
      <description>Abhijit V. Banerjee, Esther Duflo My rating: 4.28/5 This book is an account of several trials done across India and Africa tied into a larger narrative in an attempt to understand the mindset of poor and what causes poverty. It talks about what incentives and circumstances around schemes make a difference in outcomes among the poor. It also explores what priorities and biases affect their decision making when it comes to spending and credit, health care, education and entrepreneurship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/sapiens/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/sapiens/</guid>
      <description>Yuval Noah Harari, Prottasha Prachurjo Sayed Fayej Ahmed (Translator) My rating: 4.39/5 spoiler alert This is an engaging book that briefly touches on the major milestones in the evolution of human beings from the ancient paleolithic period, our sustenance alongside Denisovans and Neanderthals, ancient civilisations to the free market ideology and genetic engineering of today. The author shares a number of wonderful insights to explain why certain events panned out that led to certain characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing Good Better: How Effective Altruism Can Help You Make a Difference</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/doing_good_better/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/doing_good_better/</guid>
      <description>William MacAskill My rating: 4.25/5 This book is about evaluating altruistic actions quantitatively and presents a number of interesting cases where widely-popular well-meaning efforts fell short. It also discusses simplistic frameworks to gauge effectiveness of actions and warns against being emotionally connected to causes.
While the book doggedly mentions &amp;lsquo;doing the most good&amp;rsquo; and discourages emotional attachment, I think altruism is non-existent without emotions and cannot be discussed without that context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economics in One Lesson: The Shortest &amp; Surest Way to Understand Basic Economics</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/economics_in_one_lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/economics_in_one_lesson/</guid>
      <description>Henry Hazlitt My rating: 4.17/5 This was an okay read. The author often advocates policies without enough justifications, and which can be proved as ineffective assuming the Keynesian theory. It is replete with comparisons between a good economist and a bad economist, instructing on their generic personal traits(eg attention to detail) than how they&amp;rsquo;d decide/act in specific circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero to One: Notes on Startups, or How to Build the Future</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/zero_to_one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/zero_to_one/</guid>
      <description>Peter Thiel, Blake Masters My rating: 4.18/5 As the name suggests, 0-1 is the go-to notes for an aspiring tech start up founder. It is painfully honest and artfully brief with a lot of graphs and examples. Do read it if you hope to found a company, will hardly take a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Selfish Gene</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/the_selfish_gene/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/the_selfish_gene/</guid>
      <description>Richard Dawkins Rating 4.15/5 This is one book every person should read! Dawkins makes one question accepted norms and seeds thought-lings of bizzare possibilities . Have you ever wondered why a human fetus has more rights than an adult chimpanzee that can speak one or more human languages? Why do we think cannibalism is gross? We often consider ourselves as a nation, or a species, why not as a genus or as mammals or simply as animals and work for the collective good of say, the mammalian community!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Lie with Statistics</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/lie_with_statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/lie_with_statistics/</guid>
      <description>Darrell Huff, Irving Geis (Illustrator) My rating: 3.84/5 This is an amusing and extremely short read. Statistics is as much an art as it is a science, he claims. This book gave me an insight into the power of numbers in deception and persuasion. It alerted me to give a second thought into claims backed by stats, the major pitfalls to look for and the fact that even reputed organisations can make conscious and unconscious mistakes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tipping Point: How Little Things Can Make a Big Difference</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/tipping_point/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/tipping_point/</guid>
      <description>Malcolm Gladwell My rating: 3.99/5 This is a lesson on social-psychology: how different factors come together to cause an epidemic, be it Baltimore&amp;rsquo;s Syphilis, Coke&amp;rsquo;s successful marketing campaign or the American Revolution. Personally, it introduced to me, for the first time, the 80-20 rule(and valuing employees), the connector-maven-salesman factor and the fact that &amp;lsquo;coke&amp;rsquo; is the second most popular word in the world after&amp;rsquo;okay&amp;rsquo;. Definitely a good read. But Gladwell is no statistician or psychologist, hence don&amp;rsquo;t forget the pinch of salt!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Eat Alone: And Other Secrets to Success, One Relationship at a Time</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/never_eat_alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/never_eat_alone/</guid>
      <description>Keith Ferrazzi My rating: 3.84/5 This is a must read that emphasises on connecting with people. The author has discussed several strategies that help one to reach out farther in everyday life. While it helps to know important people, this book treats people as means rather than ends in themselves. By the author&amp;rsquo;s logic, one can put a numeric value to relationships with different people based on their influence and stature, and that is a very unromantic and utilitarian world that treats relationships as transactional and one-dimensional to an extent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictably Irrational: The Hidden Forces That Shape Our Decisions</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/predictably_irrational/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/predictably_irrational/</guid>
      <description>Dan Ariely My rating: 4.12/5 Most of us credit ourselves for being rational individuals and strive for logical consistency in things we do. If you are one, it might be a good idea to read this book and learn the edges of our reasoning. This book will make you question your honesty, your gullibility and your independence of thought. It&amp;rsquo;ll astound you how often we base decisions on seemingly insignificant factors, such as the appearance of a candidate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blink: The Power of Thinking Without Thinking</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/blink/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/blink/</guid>
      <description>Malcolm Gladwell, Barry Fox, Irina Henegar (Translator) My rating: 3.95/5 Wonderful read this is! Fast paced,intriguing and spell binding at times! I loved the progressively advancing narrative substantiated by a variety of case studies and the clear-headed line of reasoning. This book is a brilliant aggregate of human behavior, how rapid cognition influences snap decisions and how good decisions with a high statistical precision can be arrived through thin-slicing cases. Amazed me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Complete Persepolis</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/the_complete_persepolis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/the_complete_persepolis/</guid>
      <description>Marjane Satrapi Rating 4.37/5 Totally worth the three hours!
This is an insider&amp;rsquo;s perspective of Iran&amp;rsquo;s cultural revolution, when their civilisation took a reverse journey amidst war and political instability. Chilling at times, and touching at others. What endeared this book to me is the female narrative, the innocence of her childhood and the courage to confess failures. Here&amp;rsquo;s the story of a little girl who aspired to grow up to be a prophet and forced to confirm into a society of captivated females.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rich dad, Poor Dad</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/rich_dad_poor_dad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/rich_dad_poor_dad/</guid>
      <description>Robert T. Kiyosaki, Sharon L. Lechter My rating: 4.11/5 The book starts very promising seeking to counter conventional wisdom of money and investing, and presents quite a few motivational and creative ideas. However, the tone soon turns condescending where the author markets his style of investment, and lashes out at everyone and everything who does otherwise. As Keely here noted, it merely suggests what to do and intimidates the reader about the pitfalls of not doing, but the leaves the reader the figure out the logistics of &amp;lsquo;how to do to&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief History of Time</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/brief_history_of_time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/brief_history_of_time/</guid>
      <description>Stephen Hawking My rating: 4.20/5 Frankly, the book began quite promisingly and renders the reader hopes of understanding the origin of the universe. As the book proceeded, it became difficult to comprehend and finally ended with concepts like imaginary time and virtual histories all of which no makes no sense to the unassuming reader. However,it is commendable that Hawkings could put to words all of this without letting the reader taste the complicated math.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Short History of Nearly Everything</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/short_history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/short_history/</guid>
      <description>Bill Bryson My rating: 4.20/5 This is a phenomenal book that traces the scientific history of the universe and the world, as we know it. It synthesizes for a layman a number of theories and facts about the birth of the universe, particle physics, formation of earth, plate tectonics and volcanic activity, the beginning, evolution and continuous extinction of life, among other things. It also traces the scientific revolution of the last 400 years and one cannot feel but astounded at how weakly mounted on evidence are theories we regard as widely held knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freakonomics: A Rogue Economist Explores the Hidden Side of Everything</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/freakonomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/freakonomics/</guid>
      <description>Steven D. Levitt, Stephen J. Dubner My rating: 4/5 A peculiar book. Intended to puzzle but not without exaggerations. Correlation and causality are often interchangeably used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Catcher in the Rye</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/catcher_in_rye/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/bookreviews/catcher_in_rye/</guid>
      <description>J.D. Salinger My rating: 3.81/5 This is a very short book, quite a ramble though. The language is very vernacular, often plain and non-creative. It is slightly irritating at first, all the unnecessary emphasis, but one gets used to it.
I don&amp;rsquo;t see why this book is a symbol of teenage rebellion, or why people like the protagonist at all. He generalizes a lot, blames a multitude of external factors for his circumstances and hates and stereotypes almost every other character.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>