<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Policy on keerthanapg</title>
    <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Policy on keerthanapg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 17:37:56 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://keerthanapg.com/policy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Much Ado About Nothing</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/much-ado-about-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/much-ado-about-nothing/</guid>
      <description>Much Ado about Nothing Originally posted here
A closer inspection of the ‘Rally for Rivers’ fanfare
Recently, Dr Rajendra Singh, who has spend decades working on community involvement in water management, winner of the Magsaysay Award and the Stockholm Water Prize, nicknamed the ‘Waterman of India’ called out the ‘Rally for Rivers’ movement. To quote, ‘this ‘Rally for Rivers’, is not for rivers. It is for the land, for money, for power, for fame and for name’ 1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why the Sabarimala entry issue is personal? Thoughts from your run-of-the-mill Malayali woman</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/sabarimala-entry-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/sabarimala-entry-issue/</guid>
      <description>Why the Sabarimala entry issue is personal?: Thoughts from your run-of-the-mill Malayali woman Originally posted here
.. and why this affects every Indian woman
Source: 12  On September 28th, 2018, the Supreme Court of India ruled that women be granted entry at Sabarimala 6. Among other things one should note:
 Can the temple do as they please? It is been found that Ayyappa devotees do not constitute a religious denomination and as such are not immune to outside interference 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Note Of Thanks</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/note-of-thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/note-of-thanks/</guid>
      <description>A note of thanks Originally posted here
“How strongly must one love knowing that you are unconvicted felons in the eyes of the law” — Menaka Guruswamy to bench of judges at Supreme Court, July 11 2018, during the hearing of petitions against section 377.
On 6th September 2018, the Supreme Court of the largest democracy of the world struck down section 377, a colonial-era law that decriminalises homosexuality. In a unanimous verdict, with passionately written judgements, the law of our land acknowledges the naturality of alternative sexuality and holds hope for further strides for Indian queer community, namely, marriage and civic equality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are optimal ways to donate for Kerala Flood Relief and Rescue if you live abroad?</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/kerala-flood-relief/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/kerala-flood-relief/</guid>
      <description>What are optimal ways to donate for Kerala Flood Relief and Rescue if you live abroad? Originally posted here
Here we’ve made a list of options for those based in the US/outside India to contribute to relief in Kerala floods. Each of them have been verified with a US based card. Do share more in links in comments, if you’re aware and we’ll analyse/verify/update.
1. The Chief Minister’s Distress Relief Fund website has recently added the functionality to accept international cards</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Case against Simultaneous Elections in India</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/case-against-simultaneous-elections/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/case-against-simultaneous-elections/</guid>
      <description>The Case against Simultaneous Elections in India Originally posted here
During his address on National Law Day 2017, PM Narendra Modi reiterated the push for implementing simultaneous elections in India, where Lok Sabha elections and Assembly polls of all states will be synced to happen once in 5 years, citing administrative difficulties and cost to exchequer. In the later half of this year, there has been much discussion about it, with Nitish Kumar 2, the Vice President 3, the controversial India Foundation 4 and other allies in support and regional parties and the left voicing their protest 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking Out On Sexual Harassment</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/speaking-out-on-sexual-harassment/much-ado-about-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/policy/speaking-out-on-sexual-harassment/much-ado-about-nothing/</guid>
      <description>Speaking out on Sexual Harassment Originally posted here
#metoo.
When it has happened to Elizabeth Warren, why should you be reluctant to disclose.
Several times. Waking up to find a grown man sleeping next to me on the same berth, tangled in his lungi as a 10 year old on pilgrimage with parents. Or being grabbed by a frail shriveled old man in a crowded street as I visited town for the first time without parents at 13; wondering why my pee-pee area would be of interest to anyone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>