<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Random on keerthanapg</title>
    <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Random on keerthanapg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 17:37:56 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://keerthanapg.com/random/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Horse gram, Kale and Sprouts salad with Rice</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/quarantine-meals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/quarantine-meals/</guid>
      <description>Served with a side of boiled rice.
Horse Gram Stir Fried: Originally posted here
Ingredients:
 Horse gram — 1 cup Salt — 1 tbsp Water — 2 cups Green chillies — 4 Red chilli powder — 0.5 tbsp Olive oil — 2 Tbsp Garlic — 3 cloves Curry leaves — optional  Preparation:
 Boil the horse gram with water and salt in a closed container / pressure cooker until cooked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazy Sunday Morning</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/lazy-sunday-morning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/lazy-sunday-morning/</guid>
      <description>Lazy Sunday Morning Originally posted here
June 22, 2013
“It is a truth universally acknowledged, that a single man in possession of a good fortune must be in want of a wife.”
They have been special to me, and yet again, I stumbled upon these lines, as I sat up overnight to finish off David Baldacci’s thriller First Family. To talk of the book, a good plot, but the literature was just, mediocre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Hefezopf</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/hefezopf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/hefezopf/</guid>
      <description>Recipe: Hefezopf Originally posted here
(This is a creative variant of a German Easter speciality known as Hefezopf)
Ingredients:
 Flour — 400 gms Yeast — 2 tbps Sugar — 1/2 cups Butter — 2 Tbps Water Baking soda — 1/2 tsp Jam — ~10 tsps Walnuts — 1/3 cups Chocolate — 1/3 cups Raisins — 1/3 cups  Mix the flour, yeast, sugar, butter, baking soda and water to create a smooth dough and let it rest for an hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Palpayasam</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/palpayasam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/palpayasam/</guid>
      <description>Recipe: Palpayasam Originally posted here
This is a traditional Malayali desert.
Expected time: 30 minutes
Ingredients:  Milk: 750mL Water Sugar: 2 Tbsp Rice: 2.5 Tbsp Ghee: 0.75 Tbsp Cashew: 50 grams Cardamom: 1 tsp  Procedure:  Melt the ghee and saute the rice and cashew in it for 1.5 minutes on high flame. Pour the milk, add sugar and cardamom and cook on low flame until rice is well cooked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to know before donating your hair?</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/donating-hair/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/donating-hair/</guid>
      <description>What to know before donating your hair? Originally posted here
This summer, I donated ten inches of my hair to Pantene Beautiful Lengths that make wigs for people suffering from cancer. In the US alone, every year about 100,000 people take chemotherapy for cancer treatment and undergo hair loss. The process of donating is fairly simple and easy though it’s important to keep a thing or two in mind.
Before - After  What to note:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Ginger-Cardamom Latte Tea</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/ginger-cardamom-latte-tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/ginger-cardamom-latte-tea/</guid>
      <description>Recipe: Ginger-Cardamom Latte Tea Originally posted here
It’s healthy, tasty and complements well when you’re working on tough assignments :P
Ingredients(makes 2 cups):
 Water — 1 cup Milk — 1 cup Sugar — based on preference Tea leaves — 2 tsps( I use Red Label brand and the strength of the tea depends on the brand somewhat. Green tea is weak) Ginger — small chunk (approx 2cm _ 2cm _ 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: BlueBerry Pancakes</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/blueberry-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/blueberry-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>Recipe: Blueberry Pancakes Originally posted here
Preparation time: 10 minutes
Ingredients:
 Blueberries(fresh/dried):150g Pancake mix: 2/3 cup Water: 1/2 cup Sugar/sugar syrup: 1.5tsp/1.5 tbsp Butter: 1 tsp (optional) Cream cheese: 0.5 tsp (optional)  Procedure:
 Mash the blueberries such that there still are small lumps. Add the flour, water and sugar and mix thoroughly to remove flour lumps. Regulate water to alter consistency. Stop when it looks like dosa batter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rains, Thieves and Broken Dreams</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/rain-thieves-broken-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/rain-thieves-broken-dreams/</guid>
      <description>Rains, Thieves and Broken Dreams Originally posted here
Sourced from Google Images  Unlike most of India that receives rains once, Kerala has two rounds of monsoons. The first of the season arrives in June when the advancing monsoons make bountiful our harvest and rake up our GDP numbers. The brief spell of unperturbed sunlight is broken by the retreating monsoons, popularly called ‘Thulavarsham’ for they occur in the month of October/’Thula’, taking their leave from the country having toured thoroughly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Easy Baked Chicken</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/easy-baked-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/easy-baked-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Recipe: Easy Baked Chicken Originally posted here
Preparation time- 35 minutes
What you need:
 Tender chicken breasts — 0.5 pounds Olive oil — 2 table spoons Ginger garlic paste — 1 table spoon Pepper finely ground — 1 teaspoon Chilly powder — 0.25 teaspoon Garam masala — a pinch Turmeric powder— a pinch Lemon — a small slice Salt — as required  How to:
 Mix the powders and ginger-garlic to a paste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeeeeeeee :)</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/keeeeeee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/keeeeeee/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Quick and Easy Pasta</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/quick-easy-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/quick-easy-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here
Sharing successful tidbits from my reluctant adventures as a student cook. :)
Ingredients:
 Pasta — 1 cup Salsa sauce — 3 table spoons Cut up veggies — 3/5 cup Soy sauce — 1 tsp Garlic powder/paste — 1/2 tsp Ginger powder/paste — 1/4 tsp Chilli powder — 3/4 tsp Parmesan Cheese grated — 1/4 cup Mayonnaise — 1.5 tsp Pepper grated — 1 tsp Butter/ghee — 1 tsp Vegetable oil — 1 tsp Tomato sauce — 1 table spoon Salt — 1 tsp Turmeric powder — a pinch  Steps:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Eventful Dream</title>
      <link>https://keerthanapg.com/random/eventful-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 17:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keerthanapg.com/random/eventful-dream/</guid>
      <description>An eventful dream Originally posted here
This is an account of a dream I had today:
It was set in the years of the freedom movement in India and World War 2. Agricultural production had failed due to drought, war, plunder and loot by the imperialists to aid war supplies. My grandmother and I, two patriots on the run, lived in a small and claustrophobic mud-walled shack with a tiny door and window, in the basement of a busy school building.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>